A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Rockefeller Boards, Series O FA324
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Rockefeller Institute
  - Rockefeller Institute - Malt Property, 1922 (Box F 091, Folder 2)
    Plat map of Malt Property (Avenue A on the west to the East River on the east, E. 63rd St. on the south to E. 64th St. on the north). Shows the location of existing buildings. Wm. A. White & Sons Real Estate; Robt. F. Thorley #20-22; SE-33.
    Handwritten on front: 2 in a circle. Handwritten on verso: Malt Env. 31.10; for files; extra copy. Red shows property leased from City to Empire Mortgage Co. COH.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Malt Property, 1903 (Box F 091, Folder 3)
    Plat map of blocks with Avenue A on the west, the East River on the east, E. 79th St. on the north, and E. 64th St. on the south. Shows the location of existing buildings. G. Knoche, Architect. May [19]03.
    Handwritten on front: 3 in a circle. Handwritten on verso: 31.10.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Malt Property, 1914 (Box F 091, Folder 4)
    Survey map of Block 1475 (Avenue A on the west to Exterior Street on the east, E. 63rd St. on the south to E. 64th St. on the north). Shows the location of existing buildings. "Surveyed as in Possession, New York, June 3, 1914. Geo. C. Hollerith, 176 B'way."
    Handwritten on front: 4 in a circle.
  - Rockefeller Institute - Department of Animal Pathology - Clyde Farm, 1915 (Box F 091, Folder 5)
    Blueprint, "Map Showing Lands of J. D. Greene, Esq.; South Brunswick Twp.; Middlesex Co., NJ. Surveyed and drawn by C. S. Sincerbeaux, Princeton, NJ, January 1915."
    Handwritten on front, 5 in a circle. Handwritten on verso "R.I. N.J. Property."
    1" = 300'
- Rockefeller Sanitary Commission
  - Rockefeller Sanitary Commission - General, 1909-1910 (Box 52, Folder 544)
    Set up to eradicate hookworm in South; planning of campaign; Dr. Stiles' reports; relation to Government. Attack by anti-child labor forces. Success of program; Frederick T. Gates proposal to move into international scene. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift paying for campaign. John D. Rockefeller's plan to liquidate Commission and transfer remaining duties and funds to Foundation; disposal of surplus funds. Correspondents include Frederick T. Gates, John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy.
  - Rockefeller Sanitary Commission - General, 1911-1916 (Box 52, Folder 545)
  - Rockefeller Sanitary Commission - Minutes of Meetings, 1909-April 4, 1913 (Box 53, Folder 546)
  - Rockefeller Sanitary Commission - Minutes of Meetings, May 5, 1913-1916 (Box 53, Folder 547)
  - Rockefeller Sanitary Commission - Newspaper Articles, 1909 (Box 53, Folder 548)
- Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial
  - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial - General, 1923-1933 (Box 53, Folder 549)
    Reports of appropriations; original John D. Rockefeller gift; policy; finance correspondence, merger with Foundation; copy of final report. Correspondents include Star J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, George Foster Peabody, Arthur Woods, Kenneth Chorley, Thomas M. Debevoise.
    33
  - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial - Lying-in Hospital, 1928-1938 (Box 53, Folder 550)
    Contribution of $2,000,000 to new building; dedicatory inscription.
  - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial - Dr. Beardsley Ruml - Correspondence, 1923-1924 (Box 53, Folder 551)
    Preparation of reports.
  - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial - Edmund E. Day - Correspondence, 1927-1928 (Box 53, Folder 552)
    Memorial activities gradually channeled into social sciences, and Dean Day appointed head of social science program. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge to supplement his salary. Day shifted to Rockefeller Foundation when social science program was transferred to Foundation.
  - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial - Gifts, 1918-1925 (Box 53, Folder 553)
    John D. Rockefeller gifts to and through Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial.
  - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial - Incorporation Correspondence, 1918-1926 (Box 53, Folder 554)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1920 statement on policy; report for 1923; activities. Correspondents include Beardsley Ruml, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    33.1
  - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial - Certificate of Incorporation, 1918, 1924 (Box 53, Folder 555)
    Plans for incorporation; choice of state; certificates of incorporation and of changes.
  - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial - Special Gifts, 1928, 1928-1944 (Box 53, Folder 556)
    Decision to disband Memorial; establishment of separate permanent memorial funds by gifts totaling $17,500,00 to American College for Girls at Constantinople, University of Chicago, Spelman College, Women's Baptist Boards and others; establishment of Spelman Fund of New York by gift of $10,000,000. Description of funds to be set up; draft of Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial final report. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, Bertram Cutler, W. Aldrich, Lefferts M. Dashiell, Willard S. Richardson, Trevor Arnett.
  - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial - Finances, 1919-1928 (Box 53, Folder 557)
    John D. Rockefeller gift; purchases and sales; financial policy. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Bertram Cutler, John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise.
    33.5
- Spelman Fund of New York
  - Spelman Fund of New York - General, 1928-1940 (Box 53, Folder 558)
    Incorporation of fund established in 1928 to provide for certain Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial activities not suitable for annexation to new Rockefeller Foundation when Memorial merged with Foundation. Allocation of funds; grants; finance correspondence; reports; appeals; liquidation. Correspondents include Arthur Woods, Thomas M. Debevoise, Bertram Cutler, Beardsley Ruml, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Lefferts M. Dashiell, T. Lamont, C. Dykstra, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard.
    33.2
  - Spelman Fund of New York - General, 1941-1953 (Box 53, Folder 559)
  - Spelman Fund of New York - Council on Intergovernmental Relations, 1941-1947 (Box 54, Folder 560)
    Organization subsidized by Spelman Fund.
  - Spelman Fund of New York - American Public Welfare Association, 1941-1956 (Box 54, Folder 561)
    Reports.
  - Spelman Fund of New York - Dr. Charles Merriam, 1936-1947 (Box 54, Folder 562)
    Merriam's appointment as chairman; his memos on policy, budget and financing; meetings, elections. Correspondents include Raymond B. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dr. Charles Merriam, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Thomas M. Debevoise, Laurance S. Rockefeller, G. T. Moffett.
  - Spelman Fund of New York - Public Administration Clearing House, 1930-1956 (Box 54, Folder 563)
    Reports on activities.
- Sealantic Fund
  - Sealantic Fund - General, 1938-1961 (Box 54, Folder 564)
    Organization of fund; its original purposes - providing funds for churches at Seal Harbor and Pocantico Hills; expansion of activities. Transfer of "Sunnyside" to Sealantic. Financial changes. Investigation of Protestant theological education. 1961 shift to Maine and Westchester family giving. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts of cash, securities, and property for Sealantic Fund purposes. Gift of paintings by Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's children for Sunnyside. 1954 gift of Fort Lee property; Riverside Drive property. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Phillip Keebler, Laurance S. Rockefeller, H. G. Rowell.
    40
  - Sealantic Fund - Bylaws, Incorporation, 1938-1939 (Box 54, Folder 565)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 1938 letter of gift; copy of by-laws.
  - Sealantic Fund - Taxation, 1939-1947 (Box 54, Folder 566)
    Tax exempt status; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s letter of interest.
  - Sealantic Fund - Gifts - June 25, 1946 Gift, 1939-1952 (Box 54, Folder 567)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift for purchase of articles of historic or cultural interest for Dr. Rowell's work.
  - Sealantic Fund - Gifts - June 25, 1946 Gift, 1953-1960 (Box 54, Folder 568)
  - Sealantic Fund - Gifts - January 21, 1948 Gift, 1947-1948 (Box 54, Folder 569)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift of $1,000,000 to subsidize Sleepy Hollow operations.
  - Sealantic Fund - Gifts - December 1953 Gift, 1953, 1955-1956 (Box 54, Folder 570)
    For purchase of Fort Lee land.
  - Sealantic Fund - Gifts - January 1955 Gift, 1954-1961 (Box 55, Folder 571)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift of $20,000,000 for theological education. Reasons for gift; distribution of funds; comments on gift; appeals for aid. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dana S. Creel.
  - Sealantic Fund - Gifts - January 1955 Gift - Letters of Appreciation (A-K), 1955-1956 (Box 55, Folder 572)
  - Sealantic Fund - Gifts - January 1955 Gift - Letters of Appreciation (L-Z), 1955-1956 (Box 55, Folder 573)
  - Sealantic Fund - Gifts - June 1955 Gift (Box 55, Folder 574)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift for Protestant Unity Center.
  - Sealantic Fund - Gifts - August 1957 Gift, 1956-1958 (Box 55, Folder 575)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift for International Missionary development.
  - Sealantic Fund - Gifts - 1957 Gift for Nursing, 1954-1959 (Box 55, Folder 576)
    Arthur Jones memo on nursing needs; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift of $1,500,000. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dana S. Creel, Mary Clark Rockefeller.
  - Sealantic Fund - Dr. Rowell's Reports, 1948-1950 (Box 55, Folder 577)
    Reports on operations at Sleepy Hollow. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Hugh Grant Rowell.
  - Sealantic Fund - Meetings, 1942-1954 (Box 55, Folder 578)
    Copies of agendas and minutes.
  - Sealantic Fund - Meetings, 1955-1956 (Box 55, Folder 579)
  - Sealantic Fund - Meetings, 1957-1961 (Box 55, Folder 580)